SIRUI ZHU

Portfolio available at : siruizhu.github.io

SELECTED PROJECTS

China's Long March to space

https://graphics.reuters.com/SPACE-EXPLORATION-MOON/0100B0BH0NZ/index.html Researching China space program and processing data. Using After effects for animations, Illustrator for rockets illustrations, using Ai2html and responsive web design. .

Apple products made in China could face tariffs by year's end

https://graphics.reuters.com/USA-TRADE-APPLE/0100B25R11Y/index.html Collaborate with a colleague. Data processing and research. Icons illustrations and interactive scrollytelling.

Treasure of architecture: China to better protect architecture relics

https://siruizhu.github.io/cultural--relics/ API to access the data. Interactive graphics showing all cultural relics names, classifications and distribution.

The past 50 years of refugees crisis

https://siruizhu.github.io/refugee project/ Exploration of 50 years refugees dataset. Python(pandas) for data cleaning and analysis, visualization using D3. Scrollytelling with interactive charts.

Hollywood Age Gap: A Visual Exploration of Age and On-Screen Romance

https://malbasi.github.io/hollywood-age-gap/ Group project: Analyse the hollywood movies age gap. Visualization using D3. Scrollytelling with interactive charts.

EDUCATION

Lede Program for Data Journalism, Columbia University

May 2018 - Dec. 2018 New York, USA

Courses: Python, data analysis with pandas, matplotlib, SQL, JavaScript, D3.js, basic machine learning (regression and prediction) and text analysis, web app development, geographic analysis with QGIS, Scrollytelling.

M.A., Broadcast Journalism, University of Sheffield

Sept. 2014 - Sept. 2015 Sheffield, UK

Portfolio: London's Chinatown Feels the Squeeze of Rent Rises (video)

B.A., Broadcasting and Compering, Wuhan University

Sept. 2010 - June 2014 Wuhan, China

Dissertation: Analysis of China Reality Show from the Perspective of Communication.

VOLUNTEER WORK

Sheffield Student Union Charity Hitchhike Mar. 2015 Wuhan Green NGO Oct. 2011 340 W 86th st # 6A New York, 10024 (646) 9449596 surizhu9@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data: Python, pandas, matplotlib, SQL, APIs,

Selenium, BeautifulSoup

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js, Ai2html

Mapping: Leaflet, QGIS, Mapbox Services: Github, Travis, Heroku Applications: Adobe Illustrator,

Photoshop, After Effects, Adobe Premiere, Final

Cut Pro, Edius

Language: Mandarin(Native) English(Professional)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Thomson Reuters | New York, USA

Data Visualization Developer intern

April 1st 2019 to present

Designing and developing interactive & static graphics for daily news and special reports.

Wuhan Dyclub Data Technology Lit.Co. | Wuhan, China

Training Supervisor Nov. 2016 - May 2018
Organized more than twenty Dyclub data
journalism online trainings. Managed and wrote
articles on Wechat channel's special column
"Weekly Data Journalism." Operated
visualization tool Dydata.io, executed data
analysis on users. Organized "Third Data
Journalism Competition" and award ceremony.

Hubei Televisions | Wuhan, China

TV Producer Mar 2016 - Oct. 2016

Produced children's reality show and wrote children's show scripts.

UK Chinese Times | London, UK

News Editor intern June 2015 - July 2015 Edited international news pieces

China National Radio | Beijing

News Editor intern Feb. 2013 - May 2013 Edited radio news, work on 2013 NPC and CPPCC reporting for two weeks.

AWARDS

Excellent Journalist of Wuhan University

June 2011

Excellent Student for University Article Writing Competition for Celebrating Xinhai Revolution 100th Anniversary Oct. 2011